NETFLIX 原创电影
"很幸运我上过战场"这是老一辈人的看法
"I was lucky to get a war." That's how the old guys saw it.
我会用余生回顾自己对历史的贡献
I'd have the rest of my life to tell folks how I'd made history.
我是2001年7月11日参军的
Well, I signed up July 11, 2001,
9.11恐怖袭击事件的两个月前
two months before that really meant something.
我喜欢说"我来为自由而战”
Oh, I'd love to say, "I'm here to fight for freedom."
但说实话 我加入预备役是为挣学费
But honestly… I joined the reserves for the college money.
我不属于这里 我为此感到羞耻
I don't belong here. And I'm ashamed of that.
伴有羞愧的战争故事才真实
A war story can't be true unless it's got some shame attached to it.
（科威特集结地 2003年3月）
嘿!奥克雷!
Hey! Ocre!
（波基米拉洛马）
你觉着怎么样?
What do you think?
波基是我养的狗的名字
Pokey was my dog's name.
米拉洛马是我小时候住的街名
Mirra loma's the name of the street I grew up on.
这是我演色情片的艺名 我要在伊拉克大干一番 懂了吗?
It's my porn name. I'm going balls deep in Iraq, get it?
明白了 聪明
Yeah, yeah. Clever.
去拆石膏吗?
That coming off?
-正要去 -很及时 装甲车部队就要出动了
-Yeah. Yeah, headin' that way. -Just in time. Armored's rollin' out.
我们要倾巢而出 马上了
This place will be a ghost town. Ticktock, ticktock. Right?
是的
Right.
嘿 如果后面见不到面 你多保重
Hey, if I don't see you for the rest of the war, be safe.
你也是
You too.
会有点压力
A little pressure.
一到十 有多疼?
Scale of one to ten, how's the pain?
十
It's a ten.
把建议药量加倍 能缓解不适感
Whatever the suggested dose, double it. That'll handle the discomfort.
不适感?我连拳都握不了 我不能带伤出征
Discomfort? Nah, I… I can't even make a fist. I can't roll out like this.
手给我看看
Let me see your hand.
-门夹伤的? -是的
-A door did that? -Yeah.
我见过有人伤更重也出征了
I've seen guys rollin' out with a lot worse.
这是其中一个潜在目标 在巴格达 这是…
Here's one of the potential targets. When you're in Baghdad, it's really quite…
加油 恩佐
That a boy, Enzo.
加油!
-Get it!
我会上《男性健康》封面 左右两个大胸女郎环抱
I'm telling you guys, I'm gonna be on the cover of men's health, fuckin' two big-old-tittied chicks on each arm,
海浪拍打着我的胸肌
waves splashing on my pecs and shit.
查特斯基 你会上《出柜》的封面
Chutsky, we're gonna see you on the cover of out magazine
两手各握一只鸡鸡 眼神里充满羞愧 像这样
with a dick in each hand and shame in your eyes. Like this.
嘿 你们闻到了吗?
Hey, you smell that?
-胆小鬼来了 -这话怎么说?
-Smells like pussy. -Why would it smell like pussy?
嘿 奥克雷
Oh, hey, ocre.
你怎么样?我们刚说到你
What's up? We were just talking about you.
-你看起来很差 -疟疾药可把我害苦了
You look like shit. That malaria pill is giving me nightmares.
-这整个地方就是场噩梦 伙计 -那大夫怎么说?
This whole place is a nightmare, man. So… what'd the doc say?
出征没问题
Yeah. I'm good.
欢迎归队
Welcome back.
-你看到装甲车部队出发了吗? -又出动了?
-Did you see armored's rolling out? -Come again?
真的吗?
Whoa! Is that true?
对 科尔往M1坦克上装弹药
Yeah. And I saw Cole loading the Abrams.
哈珀中士 我们有行动吗?
Sergeant Harper, are we staging?
-你们知道多少我就知道多少 -说说我都知道什么
I know what you know, chutsky. Come on. What do I know? Tell me what I know.
中士 如果要行动 我们该动手准备了
Hey, sarge, if we are staging, we should start moving.
命令该来的时候就会来
Guys, command will let us know when they're ready.
我在这儿待了六个星期了 哈珀中士
Army's kept me in a cage for six weeks, sergeant Harper.
该放我出去了
Ooh, time to let me out.
你的手怎么样了?
So how's the hand feel?
没什么问题
-It's not a problem. -Okay.
把杆放下来
Get the stick, huh?
你来这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
完全服从你的命令
Uh, whatever you tell me to, sergeant.
回答得很不错 但我不是问这个
That's a very good answer. But that's not what I mean.
你是个聪明人
You're a smart guy.
比他们大部分人都聪明
Smarter than most of these boys.
你不妨试试在其他地方大展拳脚?
Why aren't you being all the fuck you can be somewhere else, huh?
我参军那天刚好赶上衣服都洗了
Well, uh, it was laundry day when I signed up.
我需要免费T恤
Needed the free t-shirt.
说实话 奥克雷
Come on, ocre.
我父亲参军了 我祖父也是
I don't know. My dad was in, my granddad.
我参军也在意料之中
Something you did, you know?
步兵光荣日 哈珀中士
Glorious day for the infantry, sergeant Harper.
继续忙你的
As you were.
遵命 少校 目前形势如何 中尉?
Hooah, sergeant major. Which way is the shit rolling, lieutenant?
每况愈下 一如既往
Downhill, as always.
-就像重力作用一样 -我们上了出征名单
Just as gravity intended, son. We're being moved up the manifest.
二组打包跟我老婆一样慢吞吞的
Chalk two packs as slow as my fuckin' wife, apparently.
收到 我们一小时后准备完毕
Roger that, sir. We're gonna be about an hour till we're square here.
最好三十分钟就准备好
Well, better make it 30.
你们自豪并且准备好了吗?
You boys proud and ready?
是的 少校 自豪并且准备好了
Proud and ready, sergeant major. Proud and ready.
好 你回答得很好 步兵的美好一天
Yeah, you got that right. Beautiful goddamn day for the infantry.
波顿?不行 这家伙不行
Burton? There's no way. Not this guy.
一整天 波顿
-All day. Burton. -This little… this little…
这只娃娃脸 湿鼻子的小狗狗 爱心熊在吗?
Little baby-faced, wet-nosed puppy dog, care bear motherfucker right here?
我在外面 不知道出了什么事
Yeah, I'm outside. I don't know none of this shit's going on, right?
放烟火时我碰巧抬起头
So I'm looking up, and I swear to god, just as the first fireworks went off,
米奇飞快地穿过前门
Mitch comes flying through the front door,
满脸血 皮开肉绽 一团糟
face bloodied, mangled, just all messed up.
我余光瞥见一道白色闪电 定眼一看
And then out of the corner of my eye, i see this white flash comin'. I look over.
波顿飞快地从前门廊跑出去
It's Burton taking a running leap off my front porch.
像这样用膝盖压住他
Came down on him with the knee, like this. Boom!
他抓着他的马尾辫 拖到街中央
He grabs him by the ponytail, drags him to the middle of the street
胖揍了他一顿
and beat the brakes off of this grown man.
我以前从没见过揍得这么狠
I mean, he hit him with shit i ain't never seen before.
-没人管吗? -没有
-What, and everyone just watched? -Yeah.
该死 波顿
-Damn, Burton.
不管怎么说 我小时候他妈妈照看过我
Bottom line, his mom took care of me when I was a kid.
好吧
Yeah.
这家伙是个混蛋 活该挨揍 就这样
This guy was a piece of shit. He got what was coming to him. -That's it. -
你得去参加愤怒管理课程
You need, like… Like, anger management for that.
不用 我没事
No, I'm good.
第一小队 你可以穿过调整线
You're clear to cross phase line, Alpha.
我非常喜欢普拉提
Well, I got really into pilates.
收到 贵狮 已准备就绪 通话完毕
Roger that, noble lion. We are ready to go. Over.
伙计们 要出发了 走吧 来吧
Guys, game on. Let's go. Come on.
要么活着到巴格达要么死 各位
Baghdad or bust, bitches.
抽烟吗?
Cigarette?
不用了 谢了 我不抽烟
No, I'm good, thanks. Don't smoke.
-你要保证我的安全 -这还用说
-Keep me safe up there. -You know it.
好了 要出发了!
Yeah, let's get it up!
该你们上战场了
-Gonna ask you boys to get to your war.
我们正感受到那种灼热
Whoever built that berm,
怕了吗?会让你们害怕的
if they ain't scared, they're gonna get scared.
抓紧时间!
Double time!
出发!
March!
（伊拉克 进军巴格达 2003年3月）
-逊毙了 -是啊 还用说
-That fuckin' sucks. -Yeah, no shit.
行了 我们得从侧翼攻击
All right. Well, you're gonna have to flank.
第三小队在街对面有一队人 我可以跟他们一起发起侧翼攻击
All right. Well, Charlie team's got a… A team across the way. Maybe I could flank with them.
查特斯基 你想去吗?去吧
Oh, chutsky, you want it? Go get it, boy.
-波顿 -什么事?
-Hey, Burton. -Yeah?
烟雾弹掩护
Give me some smoke!
但别伤着那家伙 行吗?
Hey, hey, hey, but don't bum-rush the guy, okay?
上头有命令不能毁坏清真寺
Command does not want us destroying a mosque.
-避免公关上的麻烦 -自由党
-It's gonna be a bad PR problem. -Fuckin' liberals.
不是从清真寺那儿打过来的 我看到火花在那后面
I don't think it's coming from the mosque. I saw muzzle flashes behind it.
哪栋建筑?
-What building? -
我觉得他在那间旅馆
I, uh… I think he's in the hotel.
旅馆 我带这小子过去
Hotel. I'm gonna take the kid.
好了 奥克雷
-All right, ocre. -Hey, Burton!
-波顿! -定位! 就绪 准备好了吗?
-Go on, point it out! -Rockin' and rollin'. You ready?
-走!跟着我 奥克雷! -在跟
-Let's go. Follow me, ocre! -Moving.
妈的!
Oh! Shit!
妈的!该死
Fuck! Shit. Fuck me!
快走!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
好!
All right, all right!
嘿 指挥官呢?
Where's the co?
-指挥官! -过来!
-Co! -Right here, sergeant!
指挥官!过来!
Co! Get over here!
这位列兵知道枪是哪儿打过来的
All right, private here knows where the fire's coming from.
-从哪儿? -你觉得是那间旅馆吗?
-Where's it coming from? -He's thinking the hotel.
狙击手在旅馆里
He's in the hotel.
第一小队 跟着他
Alpha, follow him.
第二小队 跟着我 好了 跟着我!
Bravo, with me. All right, on me!
奥克雷!
Ocre!
我来了
You got it.
快走
Move.
就位
Set.
快走!
Move, move, move, move, move, move, move!
遭遇敌军!遭遇敌军!东南方向建筑
Contact! Contact! Southeast building.
奥克雷 掩护火力!窗外
Ocre, cover fire! Out the window.
大家上楼去!
-Guys, get the fuck up the stairs!
行了 奥克雷 掩护火力
All right. Ocre, cover fire.
我来了 你没事 你没事
I got ya. I got ya. Oh, you're good. -You're good. You're good.
别叫唤了 你没事 就是个小枪伤
Just quit your bellyaching. You're fine. Just a little gun wound.
帮我一把 帮帮我 该死
All right, help me out here. Help me out. God damn.
-他没事吧? -做点什么
-He okay? -Fuckin' do something.
对 我们没事
Yeah, we're fine. We're fine.
奥克雷 你跟我来
-All right, ocre, you're with me. -Yeah.
你 跟我来
You, follow me.
报告基地
Call it in.
贵狮 老鹰一号呼叫 请回答?
Noble lion, this is eagle one. Do you copy?
请讲 老鹰一号
Go ahead, eagle one.
狙击手不在清真寺
Sniper fire is not coming from the mosque. I repeat, not the mosque.
确定在旅馆里
It is confirmed from the hotel.
260度方向 距离呢 距清真寺大约100米?
It is, uh, 260 degrees and… What is it, about 100 meters from the mosque?
150米
Hundred and fifty.
距清真寺150米 通话完毕
And 150 meters from the mosque. Over.
楼层呢 老鹰一号?通话完毕
Do you have a floor number, eagle one? Over.
等一下 一…他们问在几楼
Wait, one… Yo, they want a fucking floor number.
楼层?要不要房间号?
Floor number? Do they want a room number, too?
这家伙是要叫客房服务吗?
Is this motherfucker ordering room service?
爬上去看看 告诉他们楼层
Get the fuck up top. Get 'em a fuckin' floor number.
妈的
God damn.
-趴下观察 -知道
-And watch your head. -Yeah.
该死
Shit. Whoo!
三楼 东南角
Yeah. Third floor, southeast corner.
-是三楼东南角吗? -对
-You say third floor, southeast corner? -Yeah.
该死
Fuck.
妈的!
Fuck that!
贵狮 老鹰二号呼叫
Noble lion, this is eagle two.
敌方狙击火力太猛
Sniper fire is too heavy.
请求空中打击 完毕
I'm suggesting an air strike. Over.
你到底在干什么?
-What the hell are you doing? -What a clusterfuck of a…
查特斯基?
Chutsky?
-就是胡闹 -嘿 不 查特斯基
-It's just such a clusterfuck. -Hey. No, no, no, chutsky.
-这整件事就是胡闹 -不行 中士 距离太近了
This whole thing is such a fucking clusterfuck. No. No, no, no. Sergeant… Hey, sergeant, we're too close.
不近 我们的位置刚刚好
We're not too close. We're right where we need to be.
我们有多长时间?我能动吗? 我们有时间撤离吗?
Sergeant, how long do we have? Can I move? Do we have time to move?
没有 我们请求了空中打击 待着
No, we don't have time to fuckin' move. We called in an air strike. Stay put.
好吧 等等
Okay. Hang on.
我们在这里坐一整天
I mean, we're sitting here all day.
热死了 我蛋都出汗了
It's hot as shit. My balls are sweating.
胳膊肘都是汗渍
Fuckin' salt stains under my arm and shit.
这就对了
-Oh, yeah.
趴好了 支援来了
Keep your head down. We've got fuckin' backup.
你完蛋了 混蛋!
You lose, motherfucker!
所以我才来巴格达 所以我才在该死的巴格达!
Oh, fuck. That's why I'm in Baghdad. That's why I'm in fucking Baghdad!
-奥克雷!你聋了吗? -什么?
-Ocre! You deaf? -What?
奥克雷!你要吐吗?
Ocre! You about to puke?
我没事
I'm good.
我们成功了 长官
Whoo! We fuckin' did it, sir.
这是我见过的最美国式的事
That was the most American shit I've ever seen.
出来吧 查特斯基 我们从北面过来
Yeah, come on out, chutsky. Walk out now. We're coming from the north.
备好奶子 堪萨斯城
Ready them titties, Kansas City.
英雄 恩佐下士 很快就要回家了
Corporal Enzo, hero, will be home soon.
好了 就这儿 就这儿停
Okay, right here. Right here. Right here.
我是个坏家伙
Oh, I'm a bad man.
-来吧 下车 -各种胸型的我都要
-Let's go. Dismount. -Yo, i'mma get all kinds of titties.
大胸 小胸 中等大小的
Big titties, little titties, fuckin' medium titties.
该死 我就直说了吧 老兄 以前我睡的都是些三流货色
Oh, shit. I'll be straight up, man. Back home I was fucking threes, fours.
有了这种谈资 我就能睡二流的
After a story like this, I'm definitely fucking fives, sixes,
要是碰到喝醉了的爱国者 还能睡个二流偏上的
maybe even a seven if I catch me a drunk patriot.
报告情况 中士?
-What's the sitrep, sergeant? -
屋顶有个伤员
Uh, we've got a wia on the roof.
第三小队正在对他进行救治
Uh, Charlie team three's medevaccing him right now.
奥克雷和我炸了一栋楼
Ocre and I blew up a building.
是啊 干得好 列兵奥克雷
Yeah, you did. All right, good job. Good job, private ocre.
他听不见你说话
Yeah, he can't hear you.
奥克雷!过来
-Ocre! -Huh? Come here.
感觉如何?
How you feel?
军饷给低了
Underpaid.
我一定向上级转达 走吧
All right. I'll be sure to pass your complaint on to management. Come on.
别让那些小圣战分子靠得太近
Hey, don't let these little mini-jihadists get too close.
他们身上会绑满炸弹
Fuckin' little bombs strapped all over 'em and shit.
各单位注意 这是塞拉利昂28
All elements, this is Sierra two-eight.
主要任务 收集所有主要情报
Primary mission, collect all primary intelligence requirements.
打包 贴好标签
Bag it and tag it.
区域已安全 但要留意
Area has been cleared. But keep your head on a swivel, boys.
欢迎来到你们的新家
And welcome to your new home.
这是要拍照什么的吗?拍一张
Is this a photo op or what? Take a picture.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
我一定要滑一下 好耶!
I gots to do this one. Yeah, boy!
嘿!别搞了
-Hey! Hey! -Bad motherfucker. Hey, knock that shit off. Come on.
-我们走 -抱歉
-Let's go, corporal. -Sorry, sergeant.
滚出去 老兄!
Get the fuck outta here, bro!
还有没有人知道要敲门才能进? 我正在享受着呢!
Does anybody fuckin' knock anymore? I'm trying to have a moment, motherfucker!
我发现萨达姆藏色情东西的地方了
Hey! Hey, I found Saddam's porn stash.
-什么?等等 -瞧啊 哦 天啊
-What? Hold up. -There's… oh, my god.
我现在就脱裤子!
I'm taking off my pants now!
嘿 《炮弹飞车》《最长的一码》 《印第安人乔》《卖命生涯》
Oh, yeah, cannonball run, the longest yard, navajo Joe, hooper.
不是黄片 是伯特雷诺兹的电影
This isn't porn. These are Burt Reynolds movies.
所以萨达姆才会留那种胡子
Huh, guess that explains Saddam's 'stache.
（三个月后）
你担心要是在接下来的几个月里 找不到重要证据的话
Are you worried that if we don't find significant evidence in the coming weeks and months,
我们的可信度和诚信度会受损吗?
that our credibility and the integrity of this country is in jeopardy?
我 当然…
Uh, I, of course…
我的人出发了吗?
Did my guys roll out yet?
推迟了 补给出了问题
They're running behind. Having trouble with the load.
能给我一个吗?
Uh, can I get one of those?
谢谢
Thank you.
够了吗?很好
Is that, uh, good? Good. Shukraan.
准备好了 我们出发吧
All right, motherfuckers, it's ready. Let's get it moved.
闭嘴 混蛋
Hey… shut up, motherfucker.
波顿!记得斯蒂夫贝尔托利尼吗? 大屁股的那个?
Burton! Do you remember Steph bertolini? With all the ass?
小儿麻痹症的那个妞吗?
Oh, the, uh… that chick with polio?
她没得小儿麻痹!得让我说几遍?
She did not have fuckin' polio! How many times we gotta go over this shit?
是腿有点毛病 发育不良
It was, like, a leg thing or, like, she had, like, a baby foot or something…
不可能是小儿麻痹
Oh, my god, it… It couldn't have been polio,
-因为那个在1957年时就被根除了 -你怎么知道的?
-'cause they cured that in fuckin' 1957. -And why do you know that?
因为 混蛋 我查过了
Because, asshole, I looked it up.
你查是因为你以为她得了小儿麻痹
Yeah, you looked it up 'cause you thought your girl had polio, so…
-去你的 -给
-Well, fuck you very much. -Here. Here. Here.
我要开车轧过路上每一个坑…
You know what? I'm hitting every pothole and every fuckin'…
帮我和这家伙拍张照
Let's take a picture with this guy.
-1991年他有大规模杀伤性武器 -给我通讯机 吉姆
-In 1991… -Give me the comm. -…he had weapons of mass destruction. -All right, Jim?
老鹰四号 我是老鹰六号
Uh, eagle four, this is eagle six.
不管因为什么耽搁了 尽快赶上 通话完毕
Whatever the delay, pick up the fuckin' pace. Over.
老鹰六号 我是老鹰四号
-Eagle six, this is eagle four.
我这么爱你 可你为什么讨厌我? 通话完毕
Why do you hate me when I love you so much? Over.
立刻出发 下士 通话结束
Now, corporal. Out.
好了
-You guys all right? -
-好了吗? -快 拍吧 快点
-All right, ready? -Come on, take it. Come on.
-一 二 三 美利坚! -美利坚!
-One, two, three. America! -America!
-拍得很好 -我拍得好吗?
-Oh, that's solid. -Do I look good?
-好极了! -把他抬上车
-Yeah! Look at this… -All right, load him up.
我们把他抬上车 一 二 三
Let's get him in. One, two, three.
-把着那个 -好了
-Hold this. -All right.
你们都拿我在女人方面的品位开涮
Y'all fuckin' around with my taste in women and shit.
-上车 小子 -我不坐后面
-All right, hop in, hopscotch. -No, I'm not going in the back.
-上车 -我块头最大 这没道理
Get the fuck in the car. I'm the biggest. That doesn't make sense.
中士 列兵 坐车的后面
Sergeant, private. Get in the fucking back.
他拿军阶压你了!
Oh, he pulled rank on your ass!
-你会喜欢的 -你不是在开玩笑吧?
-You're gonna love it. -You got no jokes now, huh, boy?
你可以摸他 但只能摸腰部以下
All right. You can touch him. -Just keep below the waist. -Yeah, great.
-是啊 好极了 -他要摸他的圣战鸡鸡了
-He's gonna touch his hajji peepee. -
恩佐 给他想个外号
Oh, Enzo, yo, came up with a nickname.
不能用你自己的外号
You can't come up with your own nickname, man.
除了你别人不会叫那个外号
That shit's gay. Nobody's gonna fuckin' call you by it but you.
大佬谋杀犯
Boss murderer.
-够狠 -所以我才想出这个外号
-Okay, so that's badass. -Yeah? -That is badass. -That's why I said it.
我批准了
I'mma give you that one.
该死!嘿 伙计们!
Shit. Hey! Hey, guys!
伙计们 他动了!
Guys, he just moved!
他没死!
Hey! Hey! Hey, he's not dead!
你搞什么?
What the fuck is going down?
-撑住! -打开!他没死!
-Hold up! -Open up! He moved! He's not dead!
冷静 你在说什么?
Calm the fuck down. What are you talking about?
-他他妈动了! -搞什么?
-He's fucking movin'. -What the fuck?
你他妈的在说什么?
What the hell you talking about?
-该死! -看到没?
-Oh, shit! -See?
-嘿!你疯了吗? -搞什么?
-Hey! Whoa! Are you crazy? -What the fuck?
放下枪 这里气温有43度
Will you put the gun down? It's 113 degrees, all right?
尸体回暖 所以他才会像鲶鱼一样动弹
He's thawing out. That's why he's jumping around like a catfish.
-你肯定吗? -冷静好吗?放下枪
-You sure? -Will you chill out? Put that shit away.
不好玩 波顿!我差点吓出心脏病
This shit ain't funny, Burton, man! I almost had a fuckin' heart attack!
任务下来了
Mission came down.
今早两点 一架阿帕奇发现武器交易
0200 this morning, an apache spotted a weapons exchange.
朝装满便携火箭炮的卡车全力开火
Unleashed hell on a truck filled with rpgs.
在哪?
Hey, whereabouts are we talking?
巴库巴郊外北面的小村庄
Small village up north. Outskirts of baqubah.
打死一车恐怖分子不是问题 长官
I mean, a Toyota filled with dead terrorists… Doesn't seem like a big problem, sir.
大问题在于阿帕奇开火时 把给水站打了个大窟窿
No, the big problem is the big fucking hole we left in their water station when the apaches fired on them.
上头命令我们派人加入地面特种部队
Command wants some of our guys to attach to the sf team on the ground.
你要听席福森上尉指挥 往镇上送水
You'll report to a captain syverson and run water to the town.
-像送水工那样吗? -对 并且我们会给你们资金
-What do you mean? Like delivery boys? -That, and we're giving you some capital
让当地人配合工程师修理泵站
to get the locals working with the engineers on the pumping station.
大家都在说回国的事
Look, lieutenant, everybody's been talking about going home.
你现在却派我们去非我方控制区? 为了拍照吗?
And now you want us to go to some place we don't control. For what? A photo op?
对
Yeah.
天啊 你像是去游泳了一样
Christ. You look like you went swimming.
-后面不通风 -所以我才上到车顶棚上
-There was no ventilation back there. -Oh, that's why I ride up top.
比其他人看到了这个国家更多的景象
I see more of the country than anyone else.
给多少钱我都不上炮塔
Nah. Nah, you couldn't pay me enough to ride the turret.
遭遇敌军时 敌人都朝着炮塔打
We hit shit, all the fire's coming your way, buddy.
是啊 的确是
Yeah, that's true.
可等到回国了 我会想起微风 阳光
But when we get home, I'll remember the breeze, sunshine.
就像你会想起坐在漆黑的后厢里 汗出到浑身湿透
Like you'll remember sitting in the dark, sweating your ass off.
我们是对好消息过敏还是怎么的?
Are we just fucking allergic to good news or what?
特种部队?那不是我们的活儿
Special forces? We don't do that shit.
确实
That's true.
我希望所有人都能尽心尽力 好吗?
Look, guys, I don't want anybody who's not fully on board. Okay?
要是谁不想加入 我就把你换掉
You don't want in, you let me know, and I'll get you replaced.
你们别再畏畏缩缩的了
Oh, I think you should take the tampon out of your ass.
我听够了什么绿区了
All right? I'm tired of this whole green zone shit.
我加入
I'm in.
我就他妈知道
I fuckin' knew it.
嘿 你去 我就去 你良心上过得去吗?
Hey. You go, I go. You want that on your conscience?
你是成年人吗?那就自己拿主意
Are you a grown man? Then make your own decisions.
能至少让我们给家里打个电话吗?
Can we at least get the sat phone to call home?
好的 行 这可以办到
Yeah. Yeah, I'll make it happen.
中士 你打完了吗?
Hey, sergeant, you done?
对 打完了 我就打给了未婚妻
Uh, yeah. Yeah, i was just calling my fiancée.
她怎么样?
Well, how is she doing?
没人接 转到答录机上了
I got the… the answering machine.
你跟她说了很多伊拉克的事吗?
You tell her much about Iraq?
只说了不会害她担心的事 多说有何用?
Only the stuff that won't worry her. I figure what's the point, right?
是啊 我妈以为我是炊事班的
Yeah. I mean, my mom thinks i work in the kitchen.
很傻 我告诉她大家叫我奥卡拉
I told her… It's stupid. I told her everyone calls me private okra.
可你爸呢?他参过军 你可以跟他说 他明白的
Okay. But your dad, right? He was in. You could talk to him. He gets it.
我六岁时他就离家出走了
He went awol when I was six.
你很生气吗?
That burn you up?
不 我那时太小了
No. No, I was too young.
我只记得那天他说要去买可乐
All I remember is, uh, the day he left… He told me he was going to get a coke,
接着就再也没回来了
and then just never came back.
我现在怄气只喝百事可乐
So now I only drink Pepsi out of spite.
你有什么想法?
What's on your mind, ocre?
我在想我们被派去的那个地方
I was just, uh, thinking about this place they're sending us.
-巴库巴 -对
-Baqubah. -Yeah.
那些小镇 不在我们控制之下
You know, these small towns, we don't control them.
对 和当地人的关系没这里这么简单
Yeah, it's not all yahtzee and flip-flops like it is here.
我们破坏了他们的供水系统 他们肯定不愿意看到我们
And… you know, we destroyed their water supply, so they're not gonna be happy to see us.
等我们把它修好了他们就高兴了
Yeah, but they will be when we get that water flowing again.
对
Right. Right.
我们可能会碰到更严重的事
I just think that there's a chance we're walking into something bigger.
我可没准备好
I don't think I'm cut out for that shit.
波顿很顽强 查特斯基天不怕地不怕
Burton's tough as nails, and chutsky isn't afraid of anything. I… I'm-
查特斯基看到火会把手伸进去
look, chutsky sees a fire, he sticks his hand in it.
我需要个聪明并且更有大局观的人
I need somebody smart, somebody who sees the bigger picture.
要是我不去呢?
And if I don't go?
要是你不去 那我就看走眼了
If you don't go, then I was wrong about you.
我可不想让这么个人给我断后
And I don't want anybody I was wrong about watching my back.
你自己决定 不能让我替你决定
It's up to you. You can't come out here and outsource your decision to me.
如果加入 这是电话 给家打个电话
If you're in, here's the sat phone. You got a call to make.
你卖相肯定好不了 好好干就是了
You ain't gotta look good. Just gotta do good, right?
卖相好才是最重要的
Shit. Looking good's the most important part.
他真奇怪
He's strange.
你的防弹铁板呢?
Okay, where the fuck are your plates, private?
-不怎么够了 -谁匀一块出来
-There's not enough to go around. -But… somebody cough up a plate.
拿我的吧
Here, take one of mine.
不行 波顿 你是机枪手 这样不…该死 查特斯基
No, Burton, you're top gun. That's not… fuck. Chutsky.
-我没事 -闭嘴
-Hey, sergeant, I'm good -just shut the fuck up, ocre.
你要问自己
So you gotta ask yourself,
"胸部还是背部更可能中弹?”
"am I more likely to get shot in the chest or the back?"
好好选
Choose wisely.
装备好 二十分钟后下楼集合
Okay, kit up. Downstairs in 20 minutes.
-是 中士! -出发
-Yes, sergeant! -Hold up.
-早上好 -早上好 中尉
-Morning. -Morning, lieutenant.
早上好
Morning.
水罐车 这是司机法斯
The tank. Fasi, the driver.
你好 哈珀中士
Salaam. Sergeant Harper.
简易爆炸装置可能在路面或路边 所以保持车队队形
Ied attacks up and down the way, so maintain convoy integrity.
-明白 -不许有车辆插进车队
-Roger that. -No vehicles in or out.
钱在袋子里 就这些 上车吧!
Money in the back. And that's it. Load it up!
上车
Get on it.
好好跟席福森相处 他超搞笑
Oh. Enjoy syverson. He's a blast.
天啊!
Holy shit!
藏好咯 咱俩对半分
All right, look. Hide this up your asshole, i will split it with you.
时刻保持10到15米车距 谢谢
Y'all wanna maintain 10 to 15 meters at all times. Thank you.
恩佐!上车
Enzo! Mount up.
他来了 没钱分了 奥克雷
Dad's coming. Missed out on the fucking money, ocre.
本来可以发财的 奥克雷!
We could've been rich, ocre!
（巴库巴 军马营地 2003年6月）
嘿 席福森 车队到了
Hey, sy. Convoy's pulled up.
失陪一下 先生们
Give me a moment, gentlemen.
-嘿 把水打开 -什么?
-Hey. Get that water flowing. -What?
把水打开
Get that water flowing.
听好了 退后!退后!我们走!
I say get back! Get back! Let's go! Let's go!
退后!
Get back!
波顿 别让那些混蛋靠近卡车 查特斯基 快点!
Burton, get those fuckers off that truck! Chutsky, come on!
去他妈的!
God fucking damn it!
-下来! -退后!
-Get the fuck off the truck! -Get back!
-下来 -快他妈退后!
-Get off the truck. -Get the fuck back!
-奥克雷 叫这些人退后 -是 中士
Ocre! Ocre! -I want these people back! -I know. Yes, sergeant.
-退后 -他妈的下车!
-Stay down! -Get off the fucking truck!
下去!待着别动
Get off! Stay there, okay?
让这个孩子和妇女通过
Let this kid through. Let this woman through.
妇女和儿童优先 退后!
Women and children first! Stay back!
-退后! -不!
-Get the fuck down! -No!
嘿 不 退后! 查特斯基 你没事吧?
Hey. No, get back! Chutsky, you okay?
嘿!他妈的退后!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Stay the fuck back!
各位 你们的任务很简单
All right, guys, your job is real simple.
修好供水 赢取信任和认可
You keep that water flowing, win their hearts and minds,
让伊拉克人指出敌人 为我们找出目标
and then the Iraqis start pointing fingers and giving me and the boys some targets to hit.
上尉
Captain.
-穆罕默德 -我的20块钱呢?
-Machmoud. -You got my 20?
这是穆罕默德 这些人会解决你们的供水问题
This is machmoud. These boys are gonna fix your water problem.
-还有人吗? -就这几个
Are there more? Yeah, isn't that a Daisy?
去吧
Go on. Get.
但我要20块钱 好吗? 是美元 不是第纳尔
But I want my 20, okay? Dollars, not dinars.
我给你自由和民主如何?
How about I pay you in freedom and democracy?
教了他打牌 别跟他打牌
Taught that guy Texas hold'em. Do not play him.
他是高手 来吧
Turns out he's a goddamn prodigy. Come on.
（军马营地）
这是我的房间
This one's me.
跟部落首领联系很多吗?
Have you guys had much contact with the tribal leader?
那是浪费时间 你们住这间
Sheikh's a waste of time. You ladies are in here.
别犯错 门外那些人不想你们来
Make no mistake, no one outside that gate wants you here.
好好完成任务 减少他们的不满
So you do your job and turn those roars to a whisper.
晚上 熄掉所有的灯
At night, we go dark.
有一点光亮 敌人的狙击手就会开枪
Snipers so much as see a bit of light, they will start popping shots.
好极了 谁要窗边的床位?
Lovely. Who wants the bunk by the window?
奥克雷 你睡上铺
Ocre. You're up top.
任务是送水
Mission is water distro.
行车顺序 两辆军用车 一辆水罐车
Order of movement, three vehicles, two mil, one tanker.
军用车一号 水罐车 军用车二号
Vehicle number one, tanker. Number two.
行车路线如下
Your route is as follows.
我们在这儿 泵站在这儿
We are here. Pumping station is here.
分水点在这儿 这儿还有这儿 尽可能多去几个点
Distro points here, here, and here. Hit as many as you can.
-五分钟后出发 有问题吗? -没有 长官
Wheels up in five Mikes. Any questions? No, sir.
好了 开工吧
All right. Let's go to work.
收到
Roger that.
快上车吧
Come on, mount up.
嘿 A型阳性血 我也是
Hey. "A" positive. Me too.
你怎么样?还好吗?
How you doing? You good?
是的
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
恩佐 我们要出发了 查特斯基 出发
Enzo, we're pulling out. Chutsky, we're moving.
你好 内政部要求填这个
How you doing? Civil affairs said to fill this up.
明白
Roger that.
搞什么 中士?
What the fuck, sergeant?
命令说这要花几天时间
Command said it's gonna take a couple of days.
命令说了好多
Command says lots of things,
但我告诉你 电路和水管修复 一共需要六个星期
but I'm standing here telling you two weeks for electrical and four for the pipes.
天啊
Jesus.
我手下有12个人轮班 一半负责警卫 一半负责修水泵
I got 12 guys working in shifts. Half on guard duty, half on the pump.
我们得先清理碎片 然后才能评估水管的受损程度
We have to clear the debris before we can assess the extent of the damage to the pipes.
-要想快点儿 就赶紧动手干活 -我们只管分水
You wanna go faster, roll up your sleeves. Yeah, well, we're only here to distribute the water, so…
但我带来了好消息
But, hey, I got good news.
我们会给你们找些工人 加快速度
We're gonna get you some workers, and we're gonna speed this up.
还要来更多人吗?
You got more guys on the way?
我们会找些伊拉克人 付钱给他们
Yeah, we'll get some Iraqis. We got cash to spend.
-就这样吗? -是的
-That's the plan? -That's the plan.
-付钱让伊拉克人来干? -是的
-Pay Iraqis to work? -Yeah.
你有更好的计划吗 中士?
You got a better plan, sergeant?
给我二十几个人 需时就能减半
You get me a couple dozen, it might cut your time in half.
-很好 成交 -开大点!
-Good. Done. -Turn it up!
不 开到最大!
No, all the way up!
一时半会儿完不了
It's taking forever.
这差不多就是最大了
That's as good as it gets.
你这个工程师 不能想办法让它再快点儿吗?
Well, can't you engineer, brain something up to make it go faster?
-不能 -好吧
No.
每次一小时 水罐多久能装满?
All right, so hour each way. How long does it take to fill this thing?
我想差不多45分钟吧
I'd say 45, give or take.
单程三小时
Three hours a trip.
再加上分水的时间
Plus distribution time.
但伊拉克人抓紧排队 分水就很快了
But the Iraqis line up fast. Should get their water fast.
好吧 那就是单程四小时 一天三次
Okay, so four hours and three trips a day.
安全起见 要赶在日落前完成
I mean, we're still gonna be pushing sunset to be safe.
六点钟方向出现一辆皮卡
We got a pickup truck, six o'clock!
恩佐 波顿 别让这辆车插进车队
Okay, Enzo, Burton, I don't want this guy getting in my convoy.
明白吗?
You understand?
恩佐 他想超车
Enzo, this guy's gonna try to pass!
混账!
Motherfucker!
他妈的离远点儿!
Get the fuck back!
查特斯基!这玩意坏了 你去赶一下他
Chutsky! This thing breaks, i want you descending on this guy.
稳住
Hold tight.
我要开枪了 我会开枪的 老兄
I'm gonna fucking shoot! I'm gonna take a fucking shot, man!
快他妈滚开!
-Get the fuck outta here! -
他妈的 来了
God damn it. Coming in.
我们走!
Let's go!
举起手来!
Show me your hands! Show me your hands!
下车!
Get out of the car! Get out of the car!
穆罕默德 你他妈人呢?穆罕默德!
Machmoud, where the fuck are you? Machmoud!
下车
Get out of the car!
奥克雷 你在干什么?
Ocre, what the fuck are you doing?
我说下车的时候
Ocre, when I say get out the fuckin' vehicle,
-就是要你下车 -我被卡住了
-it means get out the fuckin' vehicle. -I got stuck, sergeant.
聪明 那样更安全 奥克雷
That's a smart move. That's… that's way safer, ocre.
奥克雷 搜他身
Ocre, search him.
-上 奥克雷 -他在说什么?
-Let's go, ocre! -What is he saying?
他在说什么?
Machmoud, what the fuck is he saying?
-他说他女儿在车上 -他女儿?
-He says his daughter is with him. -His daughter?
车上有个小女孩儿
Hey. Hey, there's a little girl back here.
-她有武器吗? -没有 我觉得没有
-She armed? -No. No, I don't think so.
恩佐 检查后面的车厢
All right, Enzo, check the back.
他说他女儿病了
He's saying his girl is sick
他要送她去一个亲戚家 那个亲戚是药剂师
and he's taking her to a relative who has an apothecary.
-什么? -药剂师
-A what? -An apothecary.
药店
A pharmacy.
嗨 亲爱的 能下车吗?
-Hi, honey. - Can you step out of the vehicle for me?
嘿
Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey.
你就站到这儿
Hi. I want you… I want you to stand right there
没事 她没事
-for me, okay? -It's okay. She's okay.
检查他的腿部
Check his legs.
他说什么都没带
He say he has nothing.
恩佐?
Enzo?
-后面什么都没有 -汽车安全
-Nothing back here, sergeant. -The truck's clear.
-安全 中士 -没问题吧 恩佐?
-Clear, sergeant. -Yeah, we're good. Enzo?
安全 中士
Clear, sergeant.
好了 你现在可以回车上去了
Okay, you can step back in your car now.
查特斯基 过来
Chutsky, come here.
这些人一直都用孩子来作掩护
Look, these… these people, they use kids as cover all the time.
我们先逮捕他 再交给特种部队
I think we arrest him, we let the sf guys handle him.
这家伙给我的感觉不好
I got a bad feeling about this guy.
奥克雷 给他解开 快 给他解开
Okay. Ocre, cut him loose. Let's go, cut him loose.
听着 这钱给你女儿看病用 好吗?
Look, this is, uh… This is for your trouble and your little girl there, okay?
很抱歉带来这些麻烦
We're sorry for the trouble.
你不能再往前开了 好吗?
Okay, but hey, hey, hey. You can't drive this road anymore, okay?
我不想在这条路上看到你 告诉他
I don't wanna see you on this road. Machmoud, tell him.
-他说什么? -他不要钱
-What'd he say? -He doesn't want the money.
把车门关上
Enzo, get the door.
谁会不想要钱?
Who the fuck doesn't want money?
行了 我们走 快 走吧
All right, let's go. Come on. Let's go.
奥克雷 需要邀请吗?快点
Ocre. Ocre. You need an invitation? Come on.
快点 我们走
Move your fuckin' ass. Let's go.
我们每天上午十点都会在这里分水
We will be distributing water at this location every day at 10:00 A.M.
我们的工程师正努力修复泵站
Now, our engineers are working very hard to get your pump station fixed,
很抱歉 但我们会恢复自来水供水的
and we're very sorry about it. We're gonna get your water flowing again.
但我们需要帮助 需要工人
But we need help. We need workers.
我们会付钱给工人
And we are going to be paying each man.
每天付十小时的工资
We're willing to pay him in cash for a ten-hour work day.
让开 这个人是下一个 过来
Okay, move it along. This guy is next. Come through.
我们明天日出时再来
And we're gonna be here tomorrow at sunrise.
我们会送自愿来的人去泵站
We're gonna transfer every willing worker to the pump station.
滚后边去
Get the fuck back. All right.
帮我们来帮助你们
Help us help you.
谢谢
Thank you.
-让他们排成一队! -男人这边 妇女这边
Gimme a straight line! All right. Men over here, women over here.
这是我们在美国的方式 也是这里的方式
That's how we do it in America. That's how we're gonna do it here.
让更多小孩到我这边来 所有小孩来这边
Gimme more children. All the children up here.
退后 我不会警告你第二次
Get the fuck back. I'm not gonna tell you again.
嘿 不 下一个不是你 是他才对
Hey. Hey, no, you weren't next! You weren't next. This guy's next.
排队 好吧 你行吗?走吧
Join the line. Okay, you're good. Move on out.
你们所有人 退到线后
All of you guys… All right, fine.
好吧 接着是你 谢谢 先生
Okay, you're next. Thank you, sir.
冷静 退后
Calm down. Keep it back. Keep it back.
-恩佐 你能帮下忙吗? -退后
-Enzo, help out, will you? -Back it up. Back it up.
排队下一位 过来
-Next in line, here we go. -
嘿 慢点 退后
Hey, easy. Get back.
该你了 先生
Here you go, sir.
请退后 先生 回到排队队伍里去
Please, keep back, sir. Back in the line.
好的
Okay.
好 我们走 把他们挡住
Okay. Let's go. Back them up.
好了 让这个人过去 他没事
Okay, let this guy through. He's good.
过来排队 过来排队
You guys go around and join the line. Go around and join the line.
先到先得 好吗?
I'm serving people who've been waiting first, okay?
耶 舒服
Oh, yeah, that's good.
睡会儿吧
Let's get some sleep.
我给你搞到一部电影!
Rodriguez, I got you a movie!
-把手拿开 -我会想你的!
Keep your hands off of me.  I'll be thinking of you!
-找当地工人这事没谱了 -人呢 中士?
Well, so much for our local labor.
他们很懒
-Where the fuck is everybody at, sergeant? -Fuckin' lazy is what they are.
在这儿待得越久就越可能被袭
I got a bull's-eye on me the longer we stay here.
请求尽快撤离
Request we move this shit along.
不等了 我们走 上车
All right, we're not gonna wait any longer. Let's go. Mount up.
穆罕默德 走吧
Machmoud, come on.
奥克雷
Ocre.
怎么样了?
How we looking?
大概一半了
Like halfway.
哈珀 说好的当地人呢?
Harper, where are my Iraqis?
他们没出现 但我正想办法处理
Uh, they didn't show, but… But I'm working on it.
上尉和我待会儿会和酋长谈 你呢?有什么进展?
In fact, the captain and i have a meeting with the sheikh later. What about you? Any progress?
我的人还在研究这个系统
My team's trying to figure out this system.
-一半零部件已经停产了 -难办了
Half the parts they don't make anymore. Shit sandwich, huh?
我们会完成任务的 只要给我工人
We'll do our job. Just get me some labor.
会的
Will do.
酋长只跟我谈 由我来介绍
Sheikh's only ever talked to me, so I'll make the introduction.
脱了靴子再进去
Take your boots off when you get inside.
喝点茶 之后再谈正事
Have some chai. And after chai, get down to business.
他不喜欢你带人来访
He… he don't like that you bring more soldiers to his home.
这些大兵会给你的人分水
These soldiers are gonna give water to your people.
酋长
Sheikh.
我们想让你的人加入 行吗?
We want the inclusion of your people, okay?
我们想让他们跟我们一起 把我们弄坏的东西修好
We want them to work alongside us to help fix the problem that we caused.
在你的允许下 酋长
And with your blessing, sheikh,
你的人帮我们修好给水站
your people will help us, and get y'all's water working again.
他说这太危险了
He say this is very dangerous.
要是帮了美国人 他就会丧命
If he helps the Americans, he will pay with his life.
-他和他的人就会丧命 -我们会保护所有人
Him and his people. Yeah, we're gonna keep everybody protected, okay?
上尉和他的人会保护所有人安全
The captain and… and his men, they're gonna keep everybody safe.
他说巴库巴是两座不同的城市
He say baqubah is two different cities.
白天属于美国 夜晚属于其他人
One during the day belongs to the us, and one at night belongs to other people.
他说他的人不信任美国人
Uh, he say his people do not trust the Americans.
到了晚上 你们保护不了他们
When the night comes, you cannot protect.
告诉他…
Tell him…
我明白你的担心 真的
I understand your fear. I do.
如果没人帮我们 就没法恢复供水
But if we don't have help, there's not gonna be any water.
没有水 告诉他 穆罕默德 没有水
No water. Tell him, machmoud. No water.
他说是你们弄坏的 就该由你们修好 这是你们的问题
He say you destroyed the water, you fix it. It's your problem.
你好 欢迎
Hello. Welcome.
你好 你们是送水的吗?
Hello. You deliver water?
我们明天回来 到时候带容器来装水
Uh, yeah, we'll be back tomorrow. Bring some containers.
我们学校里有贮水池
Oh, we have tanks in the school.
我们有孩子 很多人
We have children, many people.
我们不需要太多 但需要水
We don't need too much. But we need water.
我看看我能做点什么
Yeah. Yeah, I'll see what I can do.
谢谢 我叫卡迪尔 是这所学校的负责人
Thank you. I'm kadeer. I'm the director of the school.
我是马特 见到你很高兴
Kadeer, I'm Matt. It's good to meet you.
-谢谢 先生 -祝你有愉快的一天
-Thank you. Thank you, sir. -Have a good day.
我们付钱 我们有钱 会付钱 你明白吗?
We're gonna pay, okay? We have money. We will pay. Do you understand?
他说你不了解他或他的人
He say you don't understand him or his people.
美国人来并且说会帮忙 可等你们走了呢?
Uh, the us come here and say they help. But when you leave, what will happen?
好吧 行 你把下面这句转达清楚
Okay. Right. We… I want you to be real clear about this.
问题解决前我们不会离开
We will not leave. We will not leave until the problem is solved.
他说只要我们不帮美国人 你们说的那些坏人就不会伤害我们
He say those people you say are bad will not hurt us unless we help the Americans.
他叫我们走
He wants us to leave.
听着 你这个混蛋 希望你被枪打死
Listen here, you piece of shit. I hope you get shot and fuckin' die.
别照着翻译
-Uh… -Don't translate that.
谢谢你抽时间出来
Thank you for your time, sheikh.
现在我们得干伊拉克人要干的活了 是这样吗?
So let me get this straight. Now we're doing the Iraqis' work?
伊拉克人的工钱在我们手里 对吗?
Yeah. But, we, uh… We get the Iraqis' money, right?
又不是免费做
You don't do this shit for free.
对吗 哈珀中士?
Right, sergeant Harper?
看到吗 土壤不结块?
See how the soil won't clot?
没水就不结块 不结块就没养分
No water means it can't form. If it can't form, it can't be fertile.
即使你们来之前 北边逊尼派的农民
Even before you guys came here, sunni farmers in the north
就会从巴库巴什叶派那里偷水
would steal the water from the shiites in baqubah.
你们怎么阻止?
How'd you stop it from happening?
-我们不阻止 -查特斯基!
-We don't. -Chutsky!
-这跟水无关 -我们走!
-It's not about the water. -It's full. Let's go.
是逊尼派和什叶派
It's the sunnis and the shiites.
他们总会找借口打仗
They will always find an excuse to kill each other.
这肯定算件大事
So it's definitely a thing.
-嘿 查特斯基 -在
-Yo, chutsky. -Yes.
谢了 奥克雷
Oh, thanks, ocre.
-在这个国家吗? -是的
-Is it in this country? -Yes.
-在所有国家吗? -是的
-Is it in all countries? -Yes.
现在在你身上吗?你带着吗?
Is it on you right now? Are you carrying it?
对 我们都带着
Yup. We all carry it.
我们都带着?
We all carry it?
遭遇敌军 三点钟方向! 高地 50米!
Contact, three o'clock! Contact, three o'clock! High, 50 meters!
别停 继续开
Keep moving! Keep moving! Keep moving!
开过去
Move through! Move through!
妈的!
Damn it.
老鹰六号 老鹰四号呼叫 水罐车遭遇紧急状况!
Eagle six, this is eagle four. We're fubar behind this goddamn truck!
所有人下车!分散!
Everybody out! Dispatch!
停火
Cease fire! Cease fire.
查特斯基 报告弹药情况
Chutsky, h report.
两个满弹夹 6毫米口径机枪 完毕
I got two mags, .600 link. Up, up.
收到
Roger that.
奥克雷 报告弹药情况
Ocre, h report.
两个满弹夹 完毕
Yeah, I'm two. Up, up.
-收到 穆罕默德 你没事吧? -没事
-Roger that. Machmoud, you good? -Fine, sir.
老鹰四号 老鹰六号呼叫 报告情况
Eagle four, this is eagle six. Gimme a status report.
这里是老鹰四号 我们有六个满弹夹 几百发5.56毫米口径子弹 完毕
This is eagle four. We got six mags, several hundred .556. Up, up.
收到 查特斯基 守着机枪 奥克雷
Okay, Roger that. Chutsky, stay in the gun. Ocre?
-是 -跟着我
-Yeah. -On me.
嘿 中士
Hey, sergeant.
该死 老兄
Fuck this, man.
是之前开皮卡的那个伊拉克人 我就说应该把他抓起来
Fuckin' Iraqi in the truck. I told you we should've arrested him.
我一定把你的投诉写进报告 中士 谢谢
Yeah, I'll be sure to put your complaint in my sitrep, okay, sergeant? Thank you.
妈的
Fuck it. Fuck it.
该死 我受够了
Fuck it. I'm tired of this shit.
我不管了 去他的 我要洗澡
I don't give a fuck anymore. This is bullshit. I'm taking a shower.
波顿
Burton!
-你要洗吗? -不洗
-You in on this? -No. I'm good.
行 那就洗吧
All right, this is happening.
我甚至都不看你们
-Whoo! -I'm glad I'm not even watching you guys.
-好耶! -好耶
-Oh, yeah! Oh, that's good. -Oh, yeah.
快点 回位置上去 你挺干净的
Let's go. Get back to your posts. You're good and clean.
我需要有人给我按摩后背 长官
Sir, I need someone to loofah my back, sir. Oh! Oh, yeah. Whoo!
嘿!
Hey!
妈的
Fuck.
荒谬 山那边就有一村子人
This is bullshit. There's a whole village on the other side of that hill.
我们却坐在这儿 像傻子似的干活
We're sitting here scabbing our hands like fuckin' chumps.
别担心 混蛋们 我们来搞定!
Don't worry, assholes! We got it!
他们只是害怕
They're just scared.
这算借口吗?
What is that, some kinda fuckin' excuse?
-我们都怕 -是啊 再过段时间看看
-We're all fuckin' scared, ocre. -Yeah, well, give it time.
你别往好处幻想了
You know what? You need to crawl out from behind your faggotty little rainbow.
我们在这一整天 干得腰酸背痛 给这些混蛋们弄水
All right? We sit here all day, breaking our backs gettin' these fuckers water.
转过身 他们就开枪打我们
And we turn around, they're fuckin' shooting at us.
徒劳无益
I know a loaded deck when I see one.
得看他的脖子吗?
Get to show his neck?
-就说"一个挨着一个来"-但要怎么说?
-Just say "one by one." -But how do you say it?
祝你有愉快的一天
-Have a good day. Salaam. -Salaam.
呼叫基地!
Call it out!
妈的!
Oh, shit!
呼叫基地!
Call it out!
-天啊!该死! -从哪儿打过来的?
-Jesus! Fuck! -Where's it coming from?
你看到什么了? 查特斯基 报告情况
Call it out! What do you see? Chutsky, gimme a report.
四面八方!情况糟到不能再糟了
It's coming from everywhere! We're gettin' fuckin' lit up. Jesus!
别动!趴下!
Don't move! Stay the fuck down!
波顿 不熟悉的房顶! 15米 你的正前方!
Burton, foreign rooftop! 15 meters, your 12!
我在你背后 各个方向都有人朝我们开枪
I got you. All right, we're getting tagged from all sides.
波顿 到车顶去开机枪!
Burton, get up on the truck!
军马营地 老鹰六号呼叫
Warhorse, warhorse, this is eagle six.
我们在城市广场遭遇敌军
We are in contact in the city square.
收到吗?军马营地?
Do you copy? Warhorse?
房顶有人 12点方向!
We got rooftop, twelve o'clock!
该死
Shit.
-好了 -他在那儿
-Okay. Okay. -There he is.
城市中…妈的
At the city-fuck.
恩佐!
Enzo!
-恩佐! -我在这儿 中士!已就位
-Enzo! -I'm here, sarge! I'm set!
妈的 我没子弹了
Fuck, I'm dry.
我需要弹夹!给我弹夹!
Fuck, I need a mag! I need a mag!
该死
Shit.
-看到什么了吗? -他在屋顶 我在等他露头
-See anything? -Nah. He's up there. I'm waiting for a fuckin' head.
上!
Go, go, go!
该死!
Fuck!
-移动中 -干掉他了吗?
-Get moving! -You got him?
-还没有 屋顶上至少有两个人 -好吧
-Not yet. There's at least two up there. -Okay.
-准备好上了吗?干掉他们 -准备好了
-Ready to rock? Let's light 'em up. -Yeah.
-别让他有机会开枪! -好的
-Keep his head down! -Yeah.
该死!查特斯基 等等!
Fuck! Chutsky, wait!
查特斯基!
Chutsky!
嘿 查特斯基 你还好吗?
Hey! Hey, chutsky, you okay?
伙计们 查特斯基死了!
Guys, chutsky… Chutsky's down, guys!
（迪伦查特斯基 9131）
（詹姆斯和露辛达查特斯基）
你们觉得…他家里人知道了吗?
You think, um… You think his family knows yet?
我再也不走那条土路了
I ain't running that dirt road again.
那无异于寻死
That thing is death on a fucking stick.
谁有异议
Tell me I'm wrong.
我们有进展
We're making progress.
但非常缓慢 中士
At a goddamn snail's pace, sergeant.
告诉他 波顿
Tell him, Burton.
把你对我说的话告诉他
Tell him what you said to me.
算了
Forget it.
把你对我说的话告诉他
Speak the fuck up and tell him what you said to me.
-拜托 说啊! -说吧 中士
-Please, man. Come on! -Go on, sergeant.
没关系 畅所欲言
It's okay. Speak freely.
我们有任务并且我们会完成它
That we have a job to do and we'll do it.
但继续这样下去 我们会一个个死掉
But if we stay on this course, we'll get picked off one by one.
我提议在被打死之前抽身不干了
So I say we about face the fuck up out of here before I'm folding your shit in a box.
我们为什么不能出去跟他们战斗?
Why don't we just go out and shoot 'em?
我很想给那些王八蛋们来上几枪
I wouldn't mind putting some bullets in those motherfuckers.
不行 各位 那不是我们的任务 我们是来帮助这些人的
Nope, guys. That's not our job, okay? That's not… We are here to help these people.
他们不想要我们帮助
Those assholes don't want our help.
-那我们何苦要帮他们? -是啊 这任务本身就是个错
-Why the hell should we give it to 'em? -Yeah. The mission's a loser.
连穆罕默德都知道
Even machmoud knows it.
他说我们来之前他们就为了水打仗
He said they were fighting over the water before we got here.
就算修好了他们还是要打
If we put it back to normal, that's just what normal is.
各位 给你们一晚上时间
Okay, guys, you got tonight.
一整晚都难过或是生气
Okay? You get a whole fuckin' night to be sad or angry
想怎么整理情绪就怎么来
or whatever the fuck you need to secure your shit.
明天我们就复工
And tomorrow we're punching back in.
回去执行任务
We're going back to work.
奥克雷!有人来找你
Ocre! Someone here for you.
马特先生!
Mr. Matt!
对于你朋友的死我很遗憾
Mr. Matt, I'm sorry for what happened to your friend.
你怎么来了?
Uh, why are you here?
-你说你会给学校送水 -我说我会尽力这么做
-You say you bring water to the school. -I said I'd try.
但昨天都被破坏了
That got fucked up yesterday though, didn't it?
马特先生 没有水 学校就要关闭 那里有人
Mr. Matt, with no water, the school will close. There are people there.
那里是社区中心 不仅是给孩子们的
It's a community center, not only for children.
好极了 别开枪打我们就行了
That's great. Just stop shooting at us.
我们不开枪 学校里的人不会开枪
We… we don't shoot. Not the people at the school.
我们想要的跟你们一样
We want the same thing as you do.
真的吗?是什么?
Really? What?
我们想要干净的水 而且让你们回家
We want clean water. And for you to go home.
我们一直在努力 没人愿意帮我们
We've been trying. No one will help us.
也许你们问错人了 马特先生!马特先生!
Maybe you are asking the wrong people. Mr. Matt! Mr. Matt!
我没明白 你给我好好讲讲
I don't get it. You're gonna have to talk me through this.
上头给了我们钱请当地工人
We've been given money and told to use it to get local labor.
我之前试过了 你是跟酋长谈的
I've done this before. You talk to the guy in charge, and that's the sheikh.
他说得很清楚 当地人不干
And he's been very clear that the locals will not work with us.
所以才需要有人做酋长不肯做的事
Well, that's exactly why we need somebody who's gonna do what the sheikh won't.
你觉得学校老师肯吗?
And you think a schoolteacher is the answer?
恕我直言 长官 水罐车不能用了 昨天还牺牲了一位战友
All due respect, sir, we're down a tanker and we lost a man yesterday.
我得给这些家伙打打气
I gotta activate these guys.
靠我们自己是做不到的 我请求你听下这位列兵的想法
Okay? And we can't do this on our own. I'm just… I'm requesting you hear the private out.
好吧
Fine.
列兵?
Private?
长官 我实话实说 我其实没什么计划 可是
Sir, I'm… I'm gonna be honest. I… I haven't really formulated a plan, but…
之前的办法都没用
You know, nothing we've tried is working.
这个人似乎有充足的理由跟我们合作
This man… Seems to have a legitimate reason to wanna work with us.
我们可以利用这个机会 跟社区的人接触
So maybe we could use that as an opportunity to reach out to the community.
你凭什么认为可以相信这个人?
What makes you think we can trust this guy?
我认为如果哈珀中士和我去学校 或许能想出点办法 长官
I think if sergeant Harper and I go to the school, perhaps we can figure something out, sir.
别搞砸了就行
Just don't fuck this up.
明白 长官
Roger that, sir.
这就是全部吗?
Is that all?
是的 不幸的是 没有了水罐车 我们只能带来这么多了
Uh, yeah, yeah. Unfortunately, without the tanker, that's the best we can do.
我理解
I understand.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢 谢谢
Very grateful. Thank you.
卡迪尔 你说我们找错了人
Kadeer, um, you said we were talking to the wrong people.
你能跟这里的人解释一下 我们在做什么吗?
Could you explain to the people here what we're doing, why we're here?
-他们知道 -是啊 可他们不肯帮忙
-They know. -Yeah, but they won't help.
跟美国人合作非常危险
Working with the Americans is very dangerous.
你们如何保证他们的安全?
How can you guarantee their safety?
他们跟我们合作不会被人知道 一切都通过你来进行
Well, they won't be seen collaborating with us. Everything goes through you.
你跟他们谈 你把他们带来泵站
You talk to them. You bring them to the pumping station.
不必让别人知道
Nobody has to know.
听着 条件是这样的 好吗?
Look, it's your terms, okay?
你给我们找工人 我们修好泵站供水
You bring us the workers, we give the water at the pumping station.
我们付现金给他们 还有你
And look, we're gonna pay them in cash. And you.
我不需要钱 钱是给学校的
Uh, I don't need the money. The money is for the school.
我试试跟他们说说看
I will try. I will speak with them.
嘿 穆罕默德
Hey, machmoud.
哈珀中士 大门这里 看来你的伊拉克工人到了
Sergeant Harper, main gate. Looks like your hajjis are here.
你能下来确认一下吗?通话完毕
Could you come down and verify, please? Over.
我们马上就下来
Yeah, we'll be right down.
你要工人?工人来了
You wanted workers? You got workers.
包里是什么?离那个包远点
-What's in the bag? Hey, hey. Step away from the bag.
嘿 冷静点
Hey, hey, hey, hey, calm down.
离那个包远点
-Step away from the bag. -Kadeer.
-马特先生! -叫我哈珀中士
-Mr. Matt! Mr. Matt. -My name is sergeant Harper.
各位
Guys, guys.
大家冷静…安静
I need everybody to calm… I need everybody quiet.
他带了这个包来 很可疑 里面装着精密工具
He's got this bag. I… it's suspicious. There's precision tools in there. I don't like the looks of it.
-我不喜欢它的样子 -卡迪尔 请转告 是你弟弟吗?
Kadeer. Kadeer, please tell… This is your brother?
是的 哈珀先生 我弟弟是工程师
Yes, Mr. Harper. My brother is an engineer.
他是来帮你们的
Here… here he… He is here to help you.
我们需要你弟弟打开包 给这位士兵看一下
Okay. Uh, we're gonna need your brother to show my private the contents of that bag.
-抱歉 这是程序要求 -请吧
-I'm sorry. It's procedure. -Please.
并无不敬之意
-There's no disrespect. -Please.
慢慢地
Nice and slow.
好了 好的
Okay. Okay. Perfect.
非常好
Perfect.
你能移动一下这个吗?移动这个
Yeah. Can you move this? Move this.
好的 没危险品
-Okay. -Okay, that's great. It's clean.
大家冷静
All right, everybody… Everybody, calm down.
-谢谢 -请把包放到地上
-Thank you. -Please put the bag on the ground.
告诉他站到线后面去
Machmoud, tell him to get to the back of the line.
检查还没结束
-You're still gonna be patted down. -
下士 我命令你开始搜身
Corporal, I want you to start patting guys down.
奥克雷 协助下士
-Ocre, help corporal. -Yep.
列兵 你去仔细搜一下那辆车 谢谢
Private, I want you to search that car right now. Thoroughly. Thank you.
请就站到这里
Please step up right here.
穆罕默德 快来 快翻译 穆罕默德
Machmoud, come on. -Come on, machmoud. -
他说这个零件已经停产了
He said they stopped manufacturing this piece.
这我知道 他能修好吗?
I know that. Can he fix it?
不能
He can't.
他可以造个新的
He can make a new one.
-要多长时间? -两三天
-How long does he need? -Uh, two or three days.
很好 那就造吧
Great. Have at it.
你也会说英语吗?
So you, um… You speak English too?
是的
Yes.
你怎么学的?
How… how'd you learn all that stuff?
在摩苏尔大学学的
Here, in university of mosul.
机械工程
-Ah. -Mechanical engineering.
你上大学吗?
You go to university?
没有 太贵了
No. No, no, no, it was too expensive.
上大学要交学费?不是免费的?
You have to pay to study? It's not free?
不是
Yeah.
-这里是免费的? -当然了
-What, it's free here? -Of course.
该死 在美国 没东西是免费的
Shit. Well, in America nothing's free.
艾卡 嘿
Aika. Hey.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
给 老兄 帮我给她喷一下
Here, man. Spray her for me.
好吧 为什么要喷绿色?
Huh. Okay. Hey, why do you paint her green?
在这附近晃荡 又野又不听话 人看见就开枪打
Strays around here, wild and pissed off. People shoot 'em on sight.
绿狗是好狗
Green dog, that's a good dog.
谁开枪打绿狗 我就拿他是问
Anyone shoots a green dog, they answer to me.
有什么要注意的吗?
Any tips?
别喷到她眼睛就行
Yeah, just don't get it in her eyes.
-嘿 你说她叫艾卡? -艾卡
-Hey, you said her name's aika? -Aika.
嘿 艾卡
Hey, aika.
嘿
Hey.
鲁宾逊说应该一个星期就能干完了
Robinson said we should be done in a week.
是啊 巴不得马上就到那天
Yup. Can't come soon enough.
我只想…
All I'm looking forward to…
回国去脱衣舞俱乐部
Is getting back home to the frisky kitty buffet.
-给我个… -你想见谁?
-Hmm? Getting me a -Who do you wanna see?
你想见谁?
Who you wanna see?
-梅赛德斯 -梅赛德斯
-Mercedes. -Mercedes, baby.
知道为什么吗? 因为我们多喜欢他们?
You know why. 'Cause how we like 'em, Burton?
喜欢他们魁梧敦实!
-We like 'em thick! -
你在吃什么?
What are you eating?
即食食品 通心粉和蔬菜
Mre. This is, uh… penne and vegetable.
-好吃吗? -好吃 要吃点吗?
-It's good? -Yeah, you want some?
不了 你尝过鸡肉片吗?
No. You try chicken pilaf?
-很不错啊 老兄 -鸡肉米饭
-Yeah, man. -Chicken and rice.
-你要吗? -不要
-Do you want it? -No, no.
-尝尝鸡肉 给 尝尝看 -好啊
-Try some chicken. -Okay. Here, taste.
我老婆做的
My wife, she made this.
-中士 -尝尝鸡肉
-Uh-uh, sarge. -It's not chicken.
别吃
Don't do it.
你在这儿见过几只鸡?
How many chickens do you see out here?
-给 尝尝看 -不用 我饱了
-Here, you try it first. -I'm good. I'm full.
我吃了千层面
I got lasagna and… oof!
别吃
-Don't do it. -Uh-uh.
太好吃了 你老婆真厉害
That's fuckin' amazing. My compliments to your wife.
-谢谢 -谢谢
-Thank you. -Thank you.
-我开个玩笑而已 -早跟你说过他会的
Nah, I'm joking. Yeah, i told you he would, man.
-你确定不吃点通心粉吗? -不了 真不用了
You sure you don't want some of my penne? No, really, it's… no.
真聪明
Smart man.
-是啊 -是啊
-Yeah. -
哦 不!开打了 我要揍你个屁滚尿流
♪ oh, no! The fight's out I'm about to punch your lights out ♪
他妈的退后 守住你的烤架
♪ get the fuck back guard your grill ♪
我们不能无动于衷
♪ we can't stay still ♪
-接下来的话我是认真的 -说吧
-I wanna be serious, all right? -Say it.
这是敬
This is for…
查特斯基的
This is for fuckin'… This is for fuckin' chutsky, man.
-查特斯基 -查特斯基
-Chutsky, baby. -Chutsky.
-好吗?安息吧 -想那个混球了
-Okay? R-i-p. -Miss that motherfucker.
-他喜欢这首歌 -他才不喜欢呢
-He loved this music.  -He did not fucking love this music.
只听乡村音乐
He fuckin' only listened to country music.
他很棒 很擅长这音乐
He's good. No, he's good for it.
卡迪尔和那些人呢?
Okay, where the fuck is kadeer and these guys?
好吧 恩佐 波顿 高度警戒
Okay, Enzo, Burton, full security.
穆罕默德 过来
Machmoud, come here.
借过
-Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me. -
我们这边出状况了
We got… We got a situation here.
让上级来听 重复
You're gonna have to get higher on the horn, okay? Out. Copy.
他们的基地在市中心市场这里
The downtown market here is where they are based.
他们夜间集结
They meet at night.
我想他们把武器藏在花店
The flower shop here… Is where I think they hide their weapons.
我知道那里 谢谢 很遗憾你失去了亲人
I know the place. Thank you. And we're sorry for your loss.
我不需要你的感谢
I don't need your thanks.
BJ 请送这位先生出去
Bj, would you, uh, escort this gentleman out, please?
哈珀 奥克雷
Harper, ocre.
你们觉得情报可信吗?
Do you guys think this info is credible?
看看他们对他哥干了什么
Should see what they did to this guy's brother.
他一定很想帮我们
He's got every reason to want to help us.
佩普斯?
Pepps?
感觉机不可失
Seems like too good an opportunity to pass.
不能让这条情报失去价值
Okay. Well, this intel's only gonna last so long before it goes bad,
所以我们要行动
so we got to move.
分两队 我率一队从后方合围
My guess, we can take two teams. I'll lead Alpha on the back.
我带二队攻打控制前门
I'll take bravo and make entry, hold the front.
我可以带人进去
I can get the guys in there,
但我们没有足够的卡车来封锁街道
but we don't have enough vehicles to block the street, so…
-所以需要你帮忙 -明白
-We're gonna be needin' your help. -Yeah, Roger that.
那好 一小时后召开作战会议
Good. Full brief in about an hour.
我知道 我听到你说的了 安妮
I know. I've… I heard you, Anne.
安妮 听着…你说行吗?
Anne, I… look, will you just… Will you say it?
-抱歉 我待会儿再来 -不 老兄 没事
-Shit, sorry. I'll come back. -No, man,  You're good.
即使是口是心非
Will you just say it even if you don't mean it, Anne? Just say it.
算了
No, never mind.
好吧 安妮
Okay, Anne.
你也保重
You take care too.
你可以用电话了
Hey, phone's free if you want.
你没事吧?
You good?
对 没事
Yup. Yeah. Yup.
我们终于有机会铲除这些家伙了
Hey, bro, you know, we're finally gonna get a chance to get these guys.
接着我们就能修好泵站 回家
Then we can finish the pump station, fix it, go home.
对
Yeah.
"接下来的行动对所有人来说
"There's a bullet out there for everyone…
都可能是九死一生
With their names written small on the side.
而且躲也躲不掉”
Mine is coming."
我爸以前这么说过
No, my dad used to say that.
真令人宽慰
That's comforting.
如果你仔细想想 是这样
But it is, if you think about it.
也许这次行动我会挂掉
You know, maybe… Maybe my bullet's waiting out there.
也许我50年后会因为癌症挂掉
Or maybe my bullet is cancer. Gonna hit me 50 years from now.
但我控制不了
Oh, but that's not up to me.
所以担心个什么?
So why worry?
要参加这次行动对吧?
Sure you're up for this, huh?
是的
Yeah.
-你还好吗? -我不好
-Are you good? -Hell no, I ain't good.
这可是打仗 宝贝
This is war, baby.
我就是有点怕 我手抖得
I'm just fuckin' scared, man. My hands shaking and shit, like…
-看着我 -胆小鬼
-Now look at me. Look at me. -…A little bitch.
你来开车
Now you drive this motherfucker.
我负责铲除一切障碍
And I shoot anything that gets in the way.
懂我意思吗?
You understand me?
你要保证我的安全
You keep me safe up there.
这还用说 来吧
You know it. Come on.
嘿 詹姆斯
Hey, James.
你们没问题吧?
Your boys good?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
好了 我们行动吧
All right. Let's do this.
-上车 -收到
-Mount up. -Roger that.
-奥克雷 注意正前方和右侧 -收到
Hey, ocre, I want you on twelve and three. Roger.
老鹰六号 老鹰四号呼叫 三号阻击点就位
Eagle six, this is eagle four. Blocking position three is set.
收到 老鹰四号 所有位置就位
Roger that, eagle four. All positions are set.
-你有什么发现? -有你老妈
-What you got up there, brother? -Yeah, I got your fuckin' mom up here.
遭遇敌军!
-Contact! -
遭遇敌军!请回答!
Contact! Copy?
前进!
Go, go, go.
安全!
Clear!
前进!
Let's go! Let's go!
妈的
Fuck.
妈的!
Fuck! Shit!
老鹰六号 三号阻击点呼叫! 受到攻击!
Eagle six, this is blocking position three! Under fire!
该死!
Shit!
遭遇敌军火力 六点钟方向!
Contact! Six o'clock!
收到 六点钟方向!
Roger, six o'clock!
-哪里? -一楼走廊!30米!
-Where? -First-floor porch! 30 meters!
妈的
Fucker.
该死!
Shit!
妈的!该死!
Ah, fuck! Ah, shit! Shit! Fuck!
-你还好吗? -那个狗娘养的开枪打我!
-Are you good? -No, man! The son of a bitch shot me!
你伤着哪了?
Where are you fuckin' hit? Where are you hit?
肩膀 好疼
I'm hit in the shoulder, man. This shit fuckin' burns.
恩佐中弹了!
Enzo's fuckin' hit!
待在原地! 老鹰四号 报告情况
Okay. Stay put! Stay put! Eagle four, give me a sitrep now.
好吧 该死敌军火力 老兄!
Okay. Fucking returning fire, man!
该死!妈的!
Shit! Ah, fuck!
该死!遭遇敌军 三点钟方向!
Fuck! Contact, three o'clock!
收到!三点钟方向!
Roger that! Three o'clock!
中士 你能应付六点钟方向吗?
Sergeant, you got the six?
六点钟方向我来 三点钟方向你来!
No, I got the six. Stay on three! Stay on three!
收到!
Roger! Roger!
老鹰 老鹰六号呼叫 遭遇敌军
Eagle, this is eagle six. We are in contact.
二三号阻击点遭到狙击手猛烈攻击 请回答
Blocking positions two and three taking heavy sniper fire. Copy?
挺住 老鹰六号 我们就快到了
Standby, eagle six. On the move.
-让他们上车 -收到
-Load 'em in. Load 'em in.  Roger that.
-走 装好 -车篷
-Let's go, pack it in. -It's hoods.
撤退回军马营地 重复 撤退回营地
Back to warhorse, back to warhorse. I say again, rtb, rtb.
收到 重复 撤退回营地 老鹰四号 撤退中
Roger. Copy. Returning to base. Eagle four, we are on the move.
中士说我们可以撤了!上车!
The sergeant says we can move! Get in the fuckin' truck!
我马上就上车!该死!
God damn right, I'm getting in the fucking truck! Shit!
老鹰四号 迅速撤离!快撤!
Eagle four, hightail it! Go!
中士 我们要撤吗?
Sergeant, we moving?
挺住!我们在等老鹰四号!
Yeah, yeah, hold tight! Hold tight! We're waiting on eagle four!
快撤!
Let's go!
三号点人员速来集合
Blocking position three, moving to rally point.
中士 他们到了!开车!快!
Hey, sergeant, they're here! Let's move! Let's move out! Come on!
中士!他们被击中了!倒车! 他们被击中了!回去!
Sergeant, they're hit! Move! Go back! They're hit! Move!
-倒车 -该死
-Get back, get back. -Oh, shit.
波顿!
Burton. Burton!
该死!
Oh, shit!
不!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
快点 我们得离开这里 快啊!
Come on, baby, we gotta get outta here. Come on, boy. Come on!
中士 我去了!
Fuck, sergeant, I'm out!
-快! -掩护火力!
-Come on, baby! -Cover fire!
快啊!
Come on!
快啊!我们快离开这里!
Come on, baby! Come on! Let's get out of here!
把他弄上车!
-Fuck. Fuck, fuck, fuck. -Get him in!
我来了!恩佐 你没事的! 你没事的!
I got him! Enzo, you're good! You're good! You're good!
快走!把他抬上车!
Come on, let's go! Move, move, move, move! Come on, get him in the car!
把他抬上车!
Get in the car!
帮我把他抬上车!
You gotta help me get him in!
把他抬上车!
You gotta get him in!
帮我把他抬上车!
Help me get him in, Enzo!
快点!
Come on, come on!
奥克雷 上车!
Ocre, get in!
-快点! -上车 中士!我们走!
-Go! -Get in, sergeant! Let's go!
快开!快他妈上车!
Go! Get the fuck in!
开车!快开!
Go! Go!
快走!
Move! Move! Move! Move!
你会没事的
Baby, you're gonna be all right, okay?
好吗?对 呼吸 加油 呼吸
All right? Yeah, that's right. Breathe. Come on, baby, breathe. Breathe.
你没事的 我们这是在哪?
You got it. Fuck is he?
中士 你得开快点!
Sarge is gonna get us there real quick, okay?
中士 他是我的朋友
Sarge, you gotta hurry the fuck up. You gotta hurry up, please!
他可是我的朋友 老兄
He's my friend. He's my fuckin' friend, man.
他有呼吸吗?
Is he breathing?
我不知道 他伤得很重
I don't fuckin' know, man. He's hurt pretty fuckin' bad.
他伤得很重
He's hurt bad.
呼吸 加油啊
All right, just breathe. Just breathe. Come on.
加油 对 挺住
Come on. Come on. That's right. Stay up. Stay up.
你会好的 呼吸 加油
You'll be good, baby, all right? Just breathe. Just breathe. Come on.
中士 他的情况不妙 很不妙
Sarge, he's not look… He's not looking too good, all right? He's not looking too good.
老鹰六号 命令你调回
Eagle six, you are directed to go back
作战频率二零八零零…
to your operating frequency of two-zero-eight-zero-zero in the red.
医疗兵在两分钟后到达
Medevac is two Mikes out.
拿担架来!
Get a stretcher over here! Cowboy comin' in hot!
-来 快来 把他抱起来 -我们来救你
-Come on. Let's go. Get him up. -We got you. We got you.
妈的!
Ah, fuck, man!
好 我们快走!走!
Okay, let's go! Move!
帕特 你没事吧?
-Hey, pat, you all right? -Yeah.
-把他平躺放下 放这里 -慢着!
Lay him down. Lay him down. -Right here. Right here. -Wait, wait, wait!
他会没事的
He's gonna be fine.
-嘿 伙计 -你会没事的
-Hey, man. -You're gonna be fine, Burton.
你得醒醒 伙计
You need to wake up, man.
-什么情况? -我们有两个伤员
-What have we got? -Both wounded!
一个状况稳定 一个情况危急!
One stable, one critical!
-准备转移 -把他抬起来
-All right. Get ready to move! -Get him up!
-我跟他去 -一、二、三
-I'm going with him. -One, two, three.
我跟他去 带我一起去
I'm going with him, man. Come on. Take me with him.
你还好吧?我在呢
You all right? I got you. I got you.
不会有事的!我们走!
It's gonna be okay! Let's go. Get up!
我们基地见!
We're gonna see you at base, okay?
-我们基地见! -对不起 中士
-We'll see you at base! -I'm sorry, sergeant Harper.
-恩佐 你没事的 -对不起
-Enzo, you're all right. -I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
很快再见
We'll see you soon, Enzo.
你看好波顿!
You just watch Burton!
你看好波顿 好吗?你会没事的!
You watch Burton, okay? You're gonna be good!
我们很快再见!
We'll see you soon!
你他妈的!
You fuck!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
别!够了!奥克雷!
-No! No! Ocre!
听着 别这样 拜托 这样不行
No, man. No, man. It's not like that, man. Not like that!
嘿!快他妈清醒!清醒过来!
Hey! Wake the fuck up! Wake up!
这样不行!
Not like that, man!
没事 他没事
It's okay. He's okay.
别这样
-Just don't be like that.
Just don't be like that.
别这样
It's not gonna be like that.
很煎熬的一晚 但也算有所收获
Well… a rough night, but it was not for nothing.
阿里夫 你老婆做塔吉锅了吗?
Arif, your wife make the, uh, tagine?
-什么? -鸡肉
-What? -The chicken.
今天没有
Uh, not today.
我在想他吃什么 因为我他妈的吃够通心粉了
I wonder what's he's got.  'Cause I am fucking sick of the penne.
好了
All right.
嘿 你去哪儿?
Hey, where are you going?
-嘿 -我们有意面 肉…
-Hey. -We got spaghetti and meat-
席福森上尉 席福森上尉
Captain syverson. Captain syverson!
-我们怎么办? -你们还好吗?
-What do we do? -You okay?
还好
Yeah. Yeah…
我们在东北泵站 受到简易爆炸装置攻击
We've suffered an ied attack at the northeast pump station.
有几个伤员
There are multiple casualties.
请求即刻医务和火力支援
Requesting immediate medevac and immediate reinforcements.
重复 这里是老鹰六号
Say again. This is eagle six.
我们在东北泵站 受到简易爆炸装置攻击
We have suffered an ied attack at the pump station, northeast.
请求即刻…
We're requesting immediate…
奥克雷!
Ocre!
你没事吧 伙计?没事吗?
You all right, man? Yeah?
是吗?去坐下 伙计
Yeah? Go sit down, man.
军马 九人生还 跟进 破坏
Warhorse. Nine lives. Follows. Break.
一号线 暗号 PY5439
Line one. Papa-yankee-five-four-three-niner.
Four-five-niner-one.
我重复一遍…
-I say again…
（巴格达 希拉）
这本来是件好事
It can be beautiful.
不是吗?
Can't it?
-你们感觉怎么样? -很好 少校
-How you men feeling? -Good, sergeant major.
立正
Attention.
稍息
At ease.
哈珀中士
Sergeant Harper…
休假三星期 之后到利雅得归队
Three weeks' leave to return with us in riyadh.
是 长官
Roger, sir.
列兵奥克雷
Private ocre.
送你回国如何?
What do you say we get you back on level ground?
有辆车下午两点出发
There's a convoy leaving at 1400.
送你到巴拉德机场
It'll take you to the balad flightline
一架C-130飞机会送你回国
and a c-130 will take you back to the states.
我愿意放弃休假 如果可以 我要留下
I'm happy to waive my leave, sir. If it's all the same, I'll stay.
这不是让你休假 小子
The lieutenant is not giving you leave, son.
你要回国了 列兵
You're going home, private.
不必再担心…
Sergeant major, there is no reason to be concerned about-
你的仗已经打完了
your war is over.
不 还没完
No, it isn't over.
-仗还没打完… -什么?
-The war isn't over -excuse me?
恕我直言 在巴库巴发生的事…
With all due respect, what happened in baqubah-
请求发言 长官?
permission to speak freely, sir?
说吧
Yeah.
作为列兵奥克雷的上级士官 我个人认为
As the nco in charge of private ocre, it is my opinion
他不用再向自己或他人证明什么了
that he has nothing more to prove to himself or to anybody else.
-这不是要证明什么… -奥克雷
-It's not about proving anything -ocre. Ocre.
-是时候回家了 -不
-It's time to go home, Matt. -No.
-我们就快… -别激动 孩子
-This is the time when we are -take it easy there, son.
少校 我认为有必要讨论下之前的事
Sergeant major, I think we need to talk about what happened,
并做出妥善解决
and then maybe we can fix it.
你的任务结束了!
Your job is done here!
怎么会?
How?
谁来告诉我 我的任务怎么会结束了?
No, please, someone tell me how my fuckin' job is done here,
-因为我不明白怎么会… -够了 列兵!
-because I don't see how it's -god damn it, private!
你出去吧
You're dismissed.
你现在还抽烟了?
What, you a smoker now?
他们让我去见了随军牧师
They, uh, made me see the chaplain.
牧师说什么了?
What'd he say?
这是上帝的计划
It's, uh, god's plan.
接着他问我抽不抽烟 我说不抽
Then he asked if I smoke. I said no.
他给了我这些 说我该考虑下
So, uh, he gives me these and said maybe I should consider starting.
你在想什么?
How about you? What you thinking about?
我想什么?
What am I thinking about? Uh…
我在想皇家队的比赛
I'm thinking about a royals game.
皇家队的比赛
A royals game…
提卡特啤酒
A tecate…
蒜香薯条
And garlic fries.
-蒜香薯条 -对
-Ooh, garlic fries. -Yup.
我开始想这个 其他烂事就涌上心头
I start thinking about that, and all this other shit starts rushing back, you know?
我好久没想家了
I haven't even thought about home for a long time.
我跟你说过有个上尉 叫我把裤子掖进靴子里吗?
Did I tell you some captain told me to blouse my boots today?
你相信吗?
Can you believe that shit?
初来乍到
Some dude fresh off the boat,
正事都没干过 就命令我掖好裤脚 保持军容
hasn't done a damn thing, tells me to blouse my boots and look professional.
气坏我了 不光是因为裤脚 还有…
I was fucking pissed, not just 'cause of the boot thing, but…
还有什么?
But what?
你知道 我们做的事 中士
You know, we fucking had it, sergeant.
我们一起的人 我们就快恢复供水了
The people were with us. The water was gonna flow.
那不是我们的事
It wasn't ours to have, ocre.
你没什么好自责的
-You got nothing to feel guilty about. -No, but-
不管是你做了或是没做什么
okay? For whatever you did or whatever you didn't do.
没有 我…
No, I…
在科威特时我故意弄伤自己的手 用悍马车门把手夹伤
I broke my own hand back in Kuwait. I slammed it in a Hummer door.
我当时很想摆脱这一切
Just… trying to get out of all this shit.
那你现在可以了
Well, now you can.
嘿 要抽吗?
Hey, you want these?
不要
Nope.
感觉很混乱 对吧?
Confusing feeling, ain't it?
我们一直想着回家
All we do is think about going home…
现在终于成为了现实
Now, here it is.
我什么感觉都没
I don't feel anything, sergeant major.
要过一阵子才能感觉到
Yeah, it takes a while before it kicks in.
但感觉之后会袭上心头的 相信我
But it'll catch up. Believe me.
祝你好运 孩子
Good luck, son.
少校?
Hey, sergeant major?
步兵的美好一天?
Beautiful day for the infantry?
美好的一天 孩子
Beautiful day, son.
真他妈美好的一天
Beautiful goddamn day.
好了
All right.
该走了 不然错过飞机了
Better get a move on. Gonna miss your flight.
是啊
Yeah.
另一边见
I'll see ya on the other side of the berm.
I'll see you on the other side.
真他妈美好的一天
Beautiful goddamn day.
本字幕由随缘字幕组修订制作 欢迎加群374282202一起看片◑ω◑